BASHAYER ALOSAIMI

	C	\checkmark
in		O

Motivated Information Technology graduate, with experience in Android Application Development. Enjoy working in a team environment and independently, passionate about finding solutions to IT problems, application development, database administration and data analysis. Committed to quality and efficiency.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Android developer

September 2021 – January 2022

Tuwaiq Academy, The Saudi Federation for Cybersecurity, Programming and Drones.

- Develop different ideas for mobile applications with different Design Patterns and deal with GitHub.
- Manage a project by breaking it up into several phases using agile methodology.

IT Specialist Trainee

June 2021 – September 2021

Saudi Arabia Airlines, Jeddah

- Build a new database for the Communication and Network department clearly over two months.
- Determine the design of the network infrastructure

EDUCATION

Bachelor of **Information Technology**.

GPA 4.4 / 5 | Second honors class.

College of Computer Science and Engineering, University of Jeddah.

Graduated in 2021.

PROJECTS

Book Finder App

December 2021- January 2022

 Book finder application allows you to search for any book and see the details using Google Books API, allows users to add books in favorites list to reach them any time, using Kotlin programing language.

To Do List App

September 2021- September 2021

• Develop android application that allow the user to manage his task, using Kotlin programing language.

TechSensor App

August 2020 - April 2021

• Designing and creating a smart system that control environmental risks in factories and warehouses by 24/7 monitoring and sending alerts before a danger situation expand, using Java programing language.

TECNECAL SKILLS

- Kotlin, Java.
 - Android studio.
- Design pattern.
- REST API Services
- Firebase, Fire-Store
- HTML, CSS, and JavaScript.
- Microsoft SQL Server
- Adobe XD, Figma.
- Automation

SOFT SKILL

- Problem Solving.
- Attention to details.
- Verbal and writing communication.

- Analytical Thinking.
- Planning and Management.
- Teamwork.

CERTIFICATIONS

• **ITIL** 4 Foundation

Ongoing

• Professional accreditation from (SCE) as an "Information Technology specialist"

December 2021

• Introduction to Cybersecurity course certified by **Cisco** Networking Academy.

October 2019

• IT Essentials course certified by **Cisco** Networking Academy.

November 2018